[music]
I have Bad New For
You We gna
medit
pleas Because Fin
The in koto If We All Well
Good afternoon and we are going to
start recording 100
meditations and this is the first meditation So
you can say I've been there I've
heard it all they are not called
lamrim meditation they are called bribe meditation
Why do we call them
bribe meditation If you joined the
program A
3033 About a dollar a
day everyone can
do this then you will receive 100 Videos As soon as
they are
ready you will receive them literally the
next day yes Tim Well very quickly
and if you are a grumbler and a varchun and do
not share one dollar a day then
we will send you the
video that I
recorded we will send you the video with the
United States Postal Service this is
about a week or longer
that it is a great idea to get
100 meditations and participate in the program
for only about a dollar a
day
and if you participate This means that
eci will be free forever and we will not
have to beg you for 10
dollars anymore since
this is a significant waste of time
Friends, are you ready?
Okay, don't forget. If you
make these sounds in this meditation,
it will last 100 years. It's
clear you know us, four brothers, and
we are such hooligans. We are
quiet but destructive force, so we
sit quietly. I don't know if your son will do this or make
such a sound. Friends, are you ready? Absolutely
fine. The meditation is supposed to
last half an hour, but the first meditation, Tim, I
think, will be 45 minutes, so please get
ready. Let's
maintain a meditative mood. Here we are again. So
please arrange yourself. Take
a pose, clear your
throat. Put a
slight smile on your
face,
and I prefer to slightly
pull in your stomach. This helps
support your back in meditation.
Try to relax your
forehead, relax your arms. You
can place your hands in any way, but
make sure they are
slightly relaxed. Pull your shoulders back,
look straight ahead, but close your
eyelids, eyes directed toward the
horizon with
eyelids closed. If you lower your eyes,
your chin will drop down, and then
you may feel
drowsy. If you open your eyes,
look straight ahead.
and now we will do the honor of the cycles of
breathing 100 times usually we talk about 5
cycles of breathing but I have found that counting
100 cycles completely calms my mind
so we are doing 100 cycles of
breathing the exhalation is the first half of the
cycle and the inhalation is the second We are doing
100 cycles of breathing If you start to
think about something else
Please bring your mind back to
the breathing
and do not put
too much pressure on yourself please gently
approach your own
mind Tell it Let's go back to the
breathing different thoughts will come to your mind
and when you notice this
please return your attention to the breathing exhalation inhalation
100 times
we began relax the corners of the mouth
and now we will do prepare
p first think about who you
truly admire it could be a
person in your
life it does not
have to be a religious
person it could be anyone you
truly admire
someone you want to be like it
could be You admire one
quality and not this person's whole life it
could be  This person has a special
ability to be
patient or shows excessive
amazing
kindness. Think of a person you
admire and invite them to come to you for
meditation.
This could be a famous person from the
past. I like to invite
Aria to garna Jen
kapu to meditation. It could also be someone
you haven't
met yet. We all look forward to
the day when we can
meet directly with
bumi. Maybe we can
do our meditation right now. So,
someone from the past, present, or
future whom you
admire could be someone who doesn't have the
same problem. What do you have now?
For example, if you feel a certain
impatience towards someone or
irritation, try to remember
or invite someone. Who you know is
incredibly patient. You
can visualize this person at
the level of your
forehead. You can
imagine this person the size of a
thumbnail,
approximately in front of your third eye,
floating in
the air about half a meter in front of you.
I personally like to
imagine this person in full
size, sitting next to me, very
relaxed, as if we were two friends.
meditating
and think about Why you admire
this person What quality does
this person have that you would like to
have
IM
now Imagine that you are giving a
gift to this person I like to
perform the Samantha
Badra offering and this
means that you cover the sky First
I think of the blue sky and think of that day
When the sky is completely blue
Cloudless and then I cover the
whole sky I like the red rose I
cover the whole sky with beautiful
flowers and
offer honor and praise
then We
perform recognition Think about
something that you have done in the past 2-3
days and what you are not particularly proud of Maybe
you did something wrong in
relation to another person maybe you
envied someone
Think about something unpleasant that you have
done in the past 2-3
days Of course, we have
committed many wrong
actions because it
only takes a few seconds to create
negative karma but The purpose of this third
preparatory step is to
remember one or two wrong
actions expressing your
regret is a good
practice And telling someone about what
happened is very healthy
approach if we
gain other people about our weaknesses
or mistakes
and be honest with other people.
Therefore, try to be honest
with yourself
and think about
something, maybe a bad mental
habit, and tell
this person honestly. This is a good person - this is a
friend, you can
confess to him and you will feel
cleansed. So remember
something that you have done in the past
few days and Share this with the
person with whom you are meditating
and now tell this
person something that makes you happy about the world, something that
you are proud of,
and this morning we
meditated. MAZ grief, I can say that
I
feel your meditation is good, you
did a good job during this
retreat. Because I have
meditated with many people for many years and I
feel that you have worked well,
worked hard, and you can tell this
person about your past week,
rejoice, experience
happiness honestly without
pride, rejoice that you have
made such good progress
during this week. The
next preparatory step is to
ask for
teachings. I think most of the teachings
we
receive come from
our personal interactions with
people.  I think
this happens much more often than the
teachings we receive in class.
Therefore, today and tomorrow, the next
few days, especially on the way home from the
retreat, we will have a lot of
interaction with other people,
many of us will be
traveling. Let's pray that in this world there are
some
teachings, but as we communicate and talk
with other
people, say a prayer that
people can teach
you. Some people think that sometimes teachings come to us
in the form of some kind of wrong
behavior of other people, we begin to
think about seeing more of this behavior.
I hope that I myself do not behave like this.
Therefore, ask for
teachings in good examples and in bad
examples and ask for the
ability to
recognize these teachings and ask for
the ability to learn from these
teachings. The
sixth preparatory
step is that we are surrounded by truly good people.
Sometimes I think we get used to this
and do not notice it. Therefore, try to
think of good people in your life.
Good examples could be your
friends, could be your family members,
could be public
figures, could be historical
figures. But the people around
us constantly
give us examples every day, give us
teachings.
Ask your teachers to remain in
your life.  pray that you will
know and recognize your teachers
ask the teachers to stay with you and
never leave you
After the first preparatory steps We
are doing meditation and today we will
do a short
meditation this is the first of 100
mri meditations and I think to
give honor to this this
event this is the first meditation
We will do a very important
[music]
meditation life We strive and We want to become
bahi ourselves this is a good and worthy goal
for the whole
life If we can become bahi ourselves it will be
incredibly wonderful and we will be
extremely happy and we will help other
people to become
happy to be bahi satva it is very
clear very simple what we need to do
for this
we can become true thi
satva And if we have two
different states of mind two different
kinds of attitude Sam John Sam John
first I would say rather the
second is that we
want to develop an understanding of
Where this world comes from and where
all
people come from And where this world does not come from
and this is the second absolute kind of
Bakhta understanding of cause and effect
understanding of mental
seeds understanding of what is in from from how
we treated  to other
people and in order
to achieve this second absolute
hichi we need to first develop the first
ti i this lo
that other people just like me want
happiness every day every minute of our
day we try to be happy we
try to achieve happiness and this is
good
This is a beautiful aspiration of human
life to find happiness and the first meditation
that we will do today is about a
person in your
life it could be your
friend your
employee it could be anyone a
family member choose one person
diet very short and very
simple does this person want to be
happy just like I want to be
happy all day every minute I want
something good to happen I
hope every day that but prot
[music]
now focus
think And this person is the same as me
he or she also wants to be happy he
or she also hopes every day every
moment of their
day does this person also hope
to find happiness
every minute
constantly in me there is this hope and
desire and is there they in this
person inside does this person hope
every minute
today and every day that
something good will happen and the person will be
happy Choose someone and ask yourself the
question
and this  a person also
wants to be happy every minute today and we
will remain in this state for a few
minutes and then complete the meditation it is
short but it is extremely powerful and
important and you can do it for the
next few weeks if
you want
and choose one person
and now we will complete the
meditation to leave it we
have worked well this meditation is short but
mental
karma is much more powerful than
physical karma or verbal
so every hour of meditation is
extremely powerful karma karma from the very
center of the mind from the place where
seeds are created Imagine these seeds
that we created in our meditation
just now
I like to imagine them in the
center of my mind
little golden seeds in the very center of
my mind and I like to imagine
how I share these seeds with other
people I like to imagine that it is
like the
golden glow of the sun emanating from
the center of my mind and spreading
beyond my
body like rays of Light around Buddha Then
they spread Further and further
into the world around
me I
like to
spread emit these golden
rays this radiance first
to the space around me
and
then to the whole city in which I live and this
golden  the radiance touches every person
in this city and then I expand this
radiance to the whole
state and everyone gets a light
taste of the meditation that I did and
then I like to send this radiance
even further to the ocean in my country
from the east to the west coast I
like to imagine that every resident of
my country receives this receives this
radiance and then I send it even
further across the ocean to other continents
other
countries and then this light breaks out of
this planet and
spreads into the
Sun further and further On many
planets of the Universe all people and living
beings touch this Golden
light of that good meditation that I did
today and every living being
becomes happier
and then you can slowly open your eyes
I like to
stretch well I like to do this
thing When you rub your palms against
each other my
Chinese friends taught me this and do this on your
face
your meditation is very
good I have been helping people meditate
here for about 20
years Yes we had an
anniversary
celebration And this is one of the best groups I have
ever had I
feel it I
see it I don’t know
Who conducted  meditation but you did a great
job Are there any questions
before
we tiva how long do we have a
break 15 minutes So are there any
questions
Okay my teacher used to say So you
all know yes Jess doty Je
You now need to practice her
name You can call her
ri she will look around as if you are talking to
someone else
Thank you for the meditation and
Thank you for the teaching this week
question I have such a difficult time
concentrating on one person a
lot of people come to my mind Is it possible to
do this so that I
concentrate in my
head others Yes this is great I usually
three people immediately come to mind and I
think that this is
normal but I will advise
advice regarding
meditation meditation should not be
so easy that you get tired or
bored but it should also not be
so intense that you lose
concentration and focus so decide for yourself
how
difficult to make the meditation if it is too
easy then you will start to fall asleep And if it is
too easy then
you will lose the feeling of this emotion of
helping another
person so you
need it like with the strings on a guitar they
do not need to be pulled too tight and they do
not  should be too loosely stretched
right okay
yes we need a microphone here
please
Thank you sheila for a wonderful meditation
I have a question about how
seeds ripen if
every
moment opens 1p seed if the
seeds create me, you and everyone in this
room one seed will create everything then the
next and the next and the next Do
I understand this correctly this is a good
question I would say
so we have direct experience for example like
when I look into your eyes now and
we have indirect
experience
logical when I look at you I know
that there are people sitting there I cannot
see them because I am looking at
you but I indirectly understand that there are
people there I look at you but at the same time I
realize that there are people sitting there they have not yet
jumped out to go to breakfast Yes
exactly they are really still
there so at the same time my Seminas
create a direct perception of you and in
the interval Between
this and the seeds create This indirect
indirect perception of people nearby therefore
I simultaneously perceive a room
full of
people I look at you directly
and feel with indirect perception that there are
other people So direct perception the
seeds open to directly
perceive you and  between these seeds there are
other indirect seeds and
I have
indirect seeds of the fact that I
am on this planet and there are
many more people on it this happens
sequentially they do not unfold
simultaneously the human mind is not the mind of a Buddha
in this mind only one perception can occur
per millisecond of
time Therefore I cannot perceive
you
in the same millisecond to
be aware of the people sitting in that corner of
the room the mind constantly rushes back and forth back and forth
from you to them and back but the
direct object and indirect indirect
objects are created by separate seeds and
they unfold sequentially one after
another and very, very quickly and in
fact in or
indirect depends on the pictures in my mind
So in this sense there is no
difference between direct and indirect
perception pictures that create
you pictures that unfold from
my karmic seeds and this picture
by the way does not
change therefore I have these
direct pictures and then indirect
pictures but they are all pictures
this happens extremely
quickly and it is not a perfect process as
if you are putting together a mosaic from puzzle
pieces and you are always busy with one
part  puzzle and the other part is somewhere in
the dark and our perception is also
very strong withdrawal
at the same time can be perceived yes
stop throwing things
there
flights Good morning Thank you for the
wonderful
meditation my
question If the
seed never touches the
tree when it comes to Kasa qi connections
if I want to get this then I will do it then how does it
ever come into contact with
what I want Please help me
understand these
connections how why how does this
happen Good
question certain
questions certain questions
are a logical consequence of the
correct way of thinking you
see after some time of study
You should have certain
questions if you don't have them then you are doing
something wrong Teach I like it when
people ask certain questions I
understand that they are thinking If you haven't
thought about this question then you should have
thought about it so if
you have a pen and you write something on a
piece of
paper then there is a very strong feeling of
your ignorance misunderstanding
now I don't like to
call it ignorance anymore I like to
call it misunderstanding
erroneous  Ignorance can mean a
lack of knowledge and misunderstanding
means incorrect knowledge
distorted knowledge So a piece of paper and
you write with a
pen and it looks
like the pen leaves marks these marks on the
paper and you may
think ignorance understanding
incorrectly You may think that the pen
leaves these marks on the paper and it is a
mistake to think like this a mistake and
it is completely
natural to think like this it is natural
because we are in samsara because you
think that the pen writes on the paper
therefore you suffer and remain in this
suffering world because you believe in
this you think that cause and effect
means that the ink in the pen leaves
these marks marks on the paper and you
think that this is cause and effect
Therefore you try to get
more pens you work So that you have so that you have
more pens you think
that this is cause and effect But what
actually
happens the seeds of the pen open seeds pen Pen Pen Pen
seeds of paper pen paper pen paper writing letter letter letter
your mind your seeds
create
paper then your seeds create a hand and a
pen and your senada k which appear
from under  pen but the pen does not create these
letters
it is very difficult to understand and comprehend Yes,
there is cause and effect When you
write on a piece of paper but they are not connected in any way
with either the pen or the
paper all these are seeds in your
mind which are
images one on top of
another seeming cause and effect
which are not
trying to get obvious causes and
effects again and again and again
this is the cause of samsara trying to get
more pens to make sure that
others have fewer pens this is
samsara
inra is given by understanding these Pictures
are revealed one after another
ism in the example with the tree there is a seed seed seed seed
water sunlight
fertilizer and then suddenly a
tree appears but it does not come from the
seed the seed comes from your
mental picture seed mental
picture seed pictures pictures picture tree tree tree
the reason is all in the mind a
seed cannot create a tree physically
it is
impossible because as you said by
the time the tree appears the
seed is no longer there
so they never touch
do not come into
contact the tip of the pen never touches
the paper never and the seed  by
definition a
seed cannot come into contact with a
tree a
tree can never come from a
seed it is
impossible so
something else must be happening and that means
your mind is creating seeds the mind is creating  the seeds the
mind creates the seeds the mind creates the tree
why then
Gela
I I can't
see why then we care about the
network of seeds if we want
trees and this is called
patterns These are your karmic patterns
samsara patterns seeds are not the
cause of plants but if you do not sow the
seeds of a plant will not grow because
this is a pattern this is a karmic
pattern in this
world
usually there are physical
seeds they need to be sown in order for a
tree to appear this is karmic these are the
patterns
that are true most of the time
until you
become a more advanced practitioner and
understand how it actually works
so in fact they are putting pressure on me
to take up fang ok
Ella one more question
microphone and by the way
this is almond milk take a
handful of almonds soak overnight
then it soaks and is ready
then throw them in a blender
add a little
water make a smoothie and then add more
water and
mix again then throw in strawberries
and
mix again and usually I don't eat until
lunch but I  I drink two or three glasses of
this
smoothie and then you don't gain weight. There are no carbohydrates in
strawberries and almonds. You
can fit into your clothes. It's
very simple. Yes, it's
all about carbohydrates and it's a very
healthy diet. It's inexpensive. I don't
need to cook anything. It saves a
lot of time. Here's a suggestion for
you. So, thank you, Gela.
Physical seeds are clear, but mental
seeds. What about
them? Is this the same pattern or
relationship? How can we fix this?
Good question.
Thank you. The question is
that I understand the answer to Tresi's question
about LKI seeds and L.
It applies to mental seeds. The idea is the
same. Yes, the idea is absolutely the same. A mental
seed does not produce a mental
picture. A mental picture does not
necessarily come from the seed. You
perceive that
it comes from the seed because you have
always done this. I will give an example from
school. Only consciousness. And that is why it is
necessary to attend translator classes in a
mixed manner. They are free. This is the wisdom of
2,500 years.
We create such a schedule so that it is
convenient for you. In fact, it is not
convenient for me. If you continue to attend these
classes, then  you will get answers to all the
questions you may ever have
in the school of only consciousness
they say that when you wipe the pink
color
you are simply looking at the pink color in
your storehouse of consciousness you are looking at how the
seed unfolds in your own
mind
outside of you there is nothing pink everything is in
your mind This is the school of only consciousness it is
not the school of the middle way but it is useful
they believed that you are looking just of your
own
mind and at this distance from the head of
ge shila there is no cup my eyes
here is the color that is where the big
question arises of the school of only consciousness well in
fact when I see the
color pink I am actually looking at a part of my
own mind according to the school of
only consciousness and then the question arises
why do I have the feeling that this
color is somewhere outside why does it seem to me
that about one meter from me why do
I have this feeling where does it
come from and the school of only consciousness
claims that you have special seeds
from
the past that create the illusion of the
distance of this distance
the illusion of the external there is a separate seed in
your
mind that creates this sensation that
the color is outside and then the
question arises the question ell and
where does this seed come from and the answer it
does not
appear and what is this  so this means
that this seed can last for a long time
that you
can't point to the first day of your
past life when you saw that the cup
was outside because it
must also have a seed that was the reason in your
past life you thought that the cup
was outside Why? Because in
the life before that you thought that the cup was outside
because
before that and so on and Western people are not
Buddhists they have serious problems with this
they say Yes This is somehow very
strange the seed comes from an old
seed and then comes from an old
old and then from an old old old
many many many lives ago but
true Buddhism says No this is not
strange you are strange it is strange to think that there
was some beginning This is the real
strangeness if you think about it it is
very stupid to think that there was a beginning
because something came from nothing
nothing comes from
nothing
Therefore somewhere in my life there was a
childhood
probably I did something good This is an
old English
song The Sound of Music right be that as it may That's all
this
seed the
impression that a
mental seed appeared and created  a mental
picture and
impression is a pattern and this pattern has
always
existed And this is not an avoidance question
When I say that it has always been like this
it is the same as your
mother said Why can't I
eat candy all the time Well, because that's how it is